Finding Aid for the Ho Young Ham Papers LSC.0697
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Books, 1873-1994; 29 boxes.
  - Subseries 3F: Yearbooks, 1932-1950
    - Silversword, Volume 32, Maui High School., 1950.; Missing cover. (Box 33, Folder 6)
- Series 4: Clothing, ca. 1900-1975 (bulk 1900-1954); 4 cartons.
  This series consists predominantly women's clothing, such as chimas (skirts), jughoris (jackets), and magoja (blouses). It also includes more Westernized pieces such as slips and shifts. Men's clothing consists of bajis (trousers) in light and quilted fabrics.
  - Cotton blanket wrappers with blue-black printed design., undated.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Pink satin chima., undated.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Blue satin brocade chima., undated.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - White satin brocade chima., undated.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Blue silk chima., undated.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Blue chima with silver embellishment., undated.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Woman's white satin brocade blouse (magoja). Worn by Hannah Ham for Ham Tai Yong's visit in 1954., 1953.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Woman's/child's white and beige cotton blouses (magoja)., undated.; 5 items. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Pink chima., undated.; 1 item. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Jughori (jackets) with ties (white, ecru)., undated.; 5 items. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Baji (trouser)., undated.; 1 item. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Baji (trouser)., undated.; 2 items. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Jacket with blue and red design on back., ca. 1975.; 1 item. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Underwear., undated.; 1 item. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Jughori (jacket), yellow, blue, and red., undated.; 1 item. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Jughori (jacket), off-white with rose brocade., undated.; 1 item. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Jughori (jacket), green brocade with maroon trim., undated.; 1 item. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Jughori (jacket), yellow brocade with maroon trim., undated.; 1 item. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Jughori (jacket), cotton., undated.; 3 items. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Jughori (jacket), brocades., undated.; 3 items. (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Jughori (jacket)., undated.; 4 items. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Jughori (jacket), pink., undated.; 4 items. (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Jughori (jacket), ecru., undated.; 1 item. (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Men's undergarment., undated.; 5 items. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Baji (trouser)., undated.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Woman's slip., undated.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Woman's shift., undated.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Woman's shift., undated.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Woman's shift in ramie cotton., undated.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Woman's slip with embroidery at waist and shoulders., ca. 1920.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Woman's cotton underwear (sok-ot)., undated.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Light ramie cotton baji (trouser) with short legs., undated.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Woman's half slip, ecru., undated.; 1 item. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Baji (trouser) in ramie cotton., undated.; 1 item. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Quilted men's baji (trouser)., undated.; 1 item. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Quilted men's baji (trouser) ecru color., undated.; 1 item. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Baji (trouser) in stiff cotton fabric., undated.; 1 item. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Two halves of men's quilted baji (trouser)., undated.; 1 item. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Cotton and ramie cotton baji (trouser)., undated.; 1 item. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Two-toned light-weight baji (trouser)., undated.; 1 item. (Box 45, Folder 7)
- Series 5: Correspondence, 1906-1984; 1.5 boxes.
  This series consists of letters to and from Ho Young Ham and members of his family. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the surname of the correspondent.
  - [Dong Souk Ham?]., 1948 September 2.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    Letter to Ho Young Ham.
  - Appenzeller, Alice R., 1944 June 13.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Chur (Hannah Ham's father)., 1906.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Fry, W.H., 1943 September 3.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    Letter to Ho Young Ham. Asks Mr. Ham to take over supervision of Sprecklesville church.
  - Gillins, Louis and Ann., 1960 December.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Hahm family., 1964 October 27.; 4 items. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    Telegram to Hannah Ham. Announcement of Tai Young Hahm's death. Includes draft of Mrs. Ham's return telegram.
  - Hahm, Henry., 1925 March 29.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Hahm, Pyong Choon., 1951-1958.; 38 items. (Box 34, Folder 8)
    Letters and cards to Clara Ham Cabrinha. Several mention Norman's daughter, Meiling, and attempts to bring her to the U.S. Letters also mention health and death of Tai Young Hahm.
  - Hahm, Pyong Choon., 1952 October 9.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 9)
    Letter to Paul Ham.
  - Hahm, Pyong Choon., 1953-1954.; 4 items. (Box 34, Folder 10)
    Letters to Ho Young Ham.
  - Hahm, Pyong Choon., 1956 July 8.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 11)
    Letter to Dora Ham Kim [?] and husband Paul.
  - Hahm, Pyong Choon., 1959-1972.; 7 items. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    Letters and cards to Hannah Ham. One speaks of Tai Young Hahm's death; it includes a brief biographical sketch.
  - Hahm, Pyong Soh., 1949-1954.; 17 items. (Box 34, Folder 13)
    Letters to Clara Ham Cabrinha. Topics include Norman's death and circumstances in Korea during the war.
  - Hahm, Pyong Soh., 1951-1952.; 2 items. (Box 34, Folder 14)
    Letter and card to Paul and Simon Ham.
  - Hahm, Pyong Soh., ca. 1951.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 15)
    Letter to Ho Young Ham and Hannah Ham. Asks if Norman was able to reach Hawaii with wife and daughter.
  - Hahm, Pyong Soh., undated.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 16)
    Letter to Norman Ham.
  - Hahm, Tai Young., 1937-1948.; 11 items. (Box 34, Folder 17)
    Letters, postcard, and greeting card to cousin Ho Young Ham.
  - Hahm, Tai Young., 1948 August 4.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Hahm, Tai Young., 1952-1959.; 4 items. (Box 34, Folder 19)
    Letter, radiogram, and greeting cards to Hannah Ham.
  - Hahm, Tai Young., 1956-1957.; 7 items. (Box 34, Folder 20)
    Letters and greeting card to Clara Ham Cabrinha.
  - Ham, Clara [Clara Ham Cabrinha]., 1950 December 23.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 21)
    Letter to Pyong Soh Hahm. Acknowledging news of Norman's death.
  - Ham, Clara [Clara Ham Cabrinha]., 1963 April 25.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 22)
    Letter to American Red Cross [?]. Possible rough draft regarding paperwork for Norman's death.
  - Ham, Clara [Clara Ham Cabrinha]., 1963 April-1963 July.; 5 items. (Box 34, Folder 23)
    Letters to Pyong Choon Hahm. Regarding Meiling Mary Ham, Norman's daughter. Includes two undated drafts.
  - Ham, Dora., 1954.; 2 items. (Box 34, Folder 24)
    Letters to Hannah Ham.
  - Ham, Elizabeth [Elizabeth Ham Rosen]., 1947-1965.; 9 items. (Box 34, Folder 25)
    Letters and cards to her family after her move to New York to marry Walter Rosen. Discusses impending marriage and its complications and her children.
  - Ham, Hannah., 1946 December 12.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Ham, Ho Young., 1950.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 27)
    Letter to Tai Young Hahm.
  - Ham, Ho Young., 1939 July.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 28)
    Letter to Pyun Ik Po.
  - Ham, Ho Young., 1943-1950.; 6 items. (Box 34, Folder 29)
    Letters to Norman Ham.
  - Ham, Ho Young., 1945 December 31.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 30)
    Letter to unknown recipient.
  - Ham, Ho Young., 1945 December 8.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 31)
    General solicitation letter for Sprecklesville Korean Methodist Church. In English.
  - Ham, Ho Young., ca. 1943 September.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 32)
    Letter to W.F. Fry. Handwritten (draft?) responding to Mr. Fry's 1943 September 3 letter.
  - Ham, Ho Young., undated.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - Ham, Ho Young., undated.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 34)
    Letter to one of his children.
  - Ham, Ho Young., undated.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 35)
    Letter to Kwon Yonng Jin.
  - Ham, Ho Young [?]., 1948 August 3.; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 36)
    Letter to son. Possibly written by Hannah Ham.
  - Ham, Hyun., 1909 October 20, 1910 April 8.; 2 items. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Ham, John., 1946, 1954.; 2 items. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    Letters to his parents.
  - Ham, Meiling Mary., 1963 May 25.; 2 items. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    Letter to Hannah Ham. One item is believed to be translation of Korean text.
  - Ham, Meiling Mary., 1967 December 24.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    Christmas card to Clara Ham Cabrinha and Hannah Ham.
  - Ham, Norman., 1941-1950.; 20 items. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    Letters to parents and siblings, mainly from Korea, discussing his impending marriage, farm/business, and newborn daughter. Also includes his last letter before his arrest and murder at the hands of the Communists.
  - Ham, Salome., 1954 April 12 & April 23.; 2 items. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Ham, Simon., 1945 May - August.; 3 items. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    Letters written to his parents and brother Paul while serving in the military. Letters reflect his experiences while at Schofield Barracks and Camp Hood, Texas.
  - Ham, Suney., ca. 1954.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    Letter to Hannah Ham.
  - Ham, Yu Bung., 1917.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    Letter to Ho Young Ham. Yu Bung Ham is a family uncle.
  - Hi Chung Kim (Mrs.)., 1957 August 16.; 2 items. (Box 35, Folder 10)
    Letter to Clara Ham. Includes original letter in Korean and English translation. Asks about teaching careers in the United States.
  - Ho, Lim Jun., 1928 February 2.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Lee, Hong Kee., 1953 October 23.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 12)
    Letter to Mr. and Mrs. Ho Young Ham.
  - Mar, Reverend C.H., undated.; 2 items. (Box 35, Folder 13)
    Letters to [?]. One letter includes hand-drawn map.
  - Oh, Choong Chung., 1955 February 3.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 14)
    Letter to Clarence Yoshioka, Chairman of Maui Boy Scouts Committee.
  - Oh, Choong Chung., 1955-1958.; 9 items. (Box 35, Folder 15)
    Letters to Paul Ham. Choong Chung Oh was a member of the Korean Consulate General in Honolulu.
  - Ow, Y.W., undated.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 16)
    Letter to Hannah Ham
  - Pyo, Song Ok., 1932.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Rosen, Walter., 1984 May-June.; 3 items. (Box 35, Folder 18)
    Letters to Clara Ham Cabrinha regarding the Korean Benevolent Society by-laws.
  - Unidentified correspondent., 1953 October 22.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 19)
    Letter to Suney Ham [Ow]
  - Unidentified letters., undated.; 5 items. (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Veterans Administration District Office., 1951 March 14.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 21)
    Letter to Ho Young Ham. Details of Norman Ham's death in South Korea.
  - Yee., 1948.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 22)
    Letter to [?]. Written on rice paper.
- Series 6: Ledgers, 1919-1949; 1.5 boxes.
  This series consists of ledgers pertaining to family activity at the Korean Methodist Church in Sprecklesville, Korean Club of Maui, Korean National Association, and Korean Red Cross.
  - [Church ledger ?]., 1934-1954.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 23)
    Front cover says "From 1934 to 1935" but notations inside show dates up to 1954.
  - Korean Methodist [Church Sprecklesville ledger ?]., ca. 1943.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Korean National Association ledger for dues paid., 1938-1940.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 25)
    Text in Korean.
  - Korean National Association ledgers., 1944-1947.; 3 items. (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Korean Red Cross ledger., 1919-1922.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - [Korean Methodist Church Sprecklesville?] Text in Korean., 1929-1942.; 3 items. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Double Entry Ledger [no organization attributed]., 1947-1949.; 1 item. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Eternal Peace Society., ca. 1940-1941.; 1 item. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Korean Club of Maui Secretary Treasurer's Financial Report., 1937 January-1939 June.; Inscription on inside cover in English. Ledger 14" x 8.5". (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Korean Methodist Church Sprecklesville dues collection ledger., 1932-1945.; 1 item. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Korean and English text.
  - Treasury Record., 1946-1947.; 14" x 6" ledger. (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Series 7: Manuscripts, 1905-1984; 3.5 boxes.
  This series consists of manuscript materials. Notable items include the diaries written by Ho Young Ham from 1905-1954. Other materials include meeting minutes for the Korean National Association, and the Korean Benevolent Society of Maui bylaws.
  - Bible writing copy., undated.; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Bound journal embossed "So Shall Thy Seed Be" and "Ho Yong Ham"., undated.; 1 item. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Newspaper clipping from Maui News, December 27, 1950, regarding Norman Ham's murder by Communist forces in Korea is glued to back inside cover.
  - Burial plot layout by rows showing the number of graves and the identity of the owner., undated.; 1 item. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Child's time-telling exercise., undated.; 1 item. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Chinese lunar calendar., undated.; 1 item. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Composition book with KEE charter, membership, and qualifications., undated.; 1 item. (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Composition notebook with Korean characters in calligraphy (ink)., undated.; 1 item. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Composition notebook with notations in Korean [ledger?]., 1919-1922.; 1 item. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Constitution and by-laws of the Korean club of Maui., undated.; 1 item. (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Copy of Korean independence proclamation., 1919, March 1.; 1 item. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Diaries., 1905-1941.; 8 items. (Box 36, Folder 10)
    Some volumes contain autobiographical information and notes on herbal medicine.
  - Diaries., 1921-1930.; 8 items. (Box 36, Folder 11)
    One volume contains Ham children's birthdates.
  - Diaries., 1930-1936.; 8 items. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    Some contain genealogy information.
  - Diaries., 1936-1950.; 8 items. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    Some contain genealogy information and holograph maps.
  - Diaries., 1944-1952.; 8 items. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Diaries., 1949-1954, undated.; 9 items. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Epworth League meeting minutes., 1937 January-1941 September.; 1 item. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    English text. Elizabeth Ham first president (nominated January 17, 1937).
  - Genealogy material possibly dating Ho Young Ham's life., undated.; 1 item. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Genealogy notes by Clara Ham Cabrinha., undated.; 1 item. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Two pages of photocopied notes. Includes short biographical note on Hannah Ham.
  - Ham family Kyo dynasty., undated.; 1 item. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Hannah Ham's writing on back of Christmas paper., undated.; 1 item. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Korean Benevolent Society of Maui notebook which includes the 1984 bylaws written by Walter Rosen., 1984 May 24.; 1 item. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    Also lists the ministers of the Korean Church in Sprecklesville from 1910 to 1954.
  - Korean Benevolent Society of Maui proposed set of by-laws written by Walter Rosen., 1984 May 24.; 4 items. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Korean drinking songs (in Chinese)., undated.; 5 items. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Korean National Association meeting minutes [?]., 1943-1952.; 3 items. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Korean National Association notebook detailing association's history., ca. 1930.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Korean provinces list., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Letter discussing Korean history., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Memo regarding year cycle of animals., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Memorandum book for K. Morihara Store, Camp One., 1939-1947.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Note detailing some family genealogy., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    English text.
  - Note in classical Chinese., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 7)
    Unidentified writer and recipient.
  - Note that includes list of names., ca. 1930 August.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Notebooks., 1938-1948.; 2 items. (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Poem written in Chinese/Korean., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Practice sheets writing Chinese language., undated.; 4 items. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Sermon., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Stenographer's notebook with notations in Korean., 1946-1947.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified manuscript., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 14)
    Has two type-written lines regarding American industry.
  - Unidentified manuscript., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 15)
    Two lines of characters.
  - Unidentified song., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Korean National Association meeting minutes., undated.; 2 items. (Box 41, Folder 7)
- Series 8: Photographs, ca. 1900-1953; 1 box.
  This series includes early photographs of Ho Young Ham and Hannah Ham with some of their children, group photographs of Korean National Association members, and several photographs of Tai Young Hahm with various Ham family members during his November 1953 visit to Hawaii.
  - Composite with two images: Yun Bong-gil surrounded by military personnel and Yun Bong-gil holding a hand grenade with sign hung around his neck., ca. 1920.; B/W matted copy print. (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Group portrait of four men and one child that includes Reverend Lim Choon Ho Min., ca. 1915.; 6.25" x 8" b/w matted print. House number in photo is 1337. (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Ho Young Ham and wife Hannah., ca. 1938.; 4.5" x 6.5" b/w print. (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Ho Young Ham, wife Hannah, and three of their young children., ca. 1907.; 5.5" x 3.75" mounted b/w print. (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - King Kojong of Korea., ca. 1900.; 4" x 5.75" b/w mounted copy print. (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Korean Christian Institute, Kalihi, Honolulu, T.H. Composite photograph that includes school house, office & girls' home, boy's dormitory, and group photo., 1930 June.; 7.75" x 9.5" b/w print. (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Korean National Association group portrait posed in front of building with Korean flags made by Hannah Ham in background., ca. 1910.; 6.5" x 8.25" b/w matted print; scanned b/w copy. (Box 39, Folder 23)
    Flags made by Hannah Ham are in this collection.
  - Korean National Association group portrait with Ho Young Ham first row, right side., ca. 1911.; B/w matted print. (Box 39, Folder 24)
    Participants identified in Korean on verso. Photographed by L.L. Kobayashi of Kahului, Maui, T.H.
  - Large group portrait of men, women, and children in front of building with Korean and American flags visible., ca. 1910.; 8.25 x 6.25 b/w matted print. (Box 39, Folder 25)
    Mat is hand inscribed "Sprecklesville, Maui" with notations in Korean below.
  - Photo print of drawing of man standing in front of Korean flag holding grenades in both hands; superimposed with list of his actions., ca. 1920.; B/w matted copy print. (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Portrait of Korean man and woman. Man is seated beside standing woman holding a book and umbrella., ca. 1910.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Portrait of Syngman Rhee., ca. 1905.; B/w matted copy print. (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Suney Ham graduation portrait by photographer Matsui in Haiku, Maui., ca. 1920.; B/w matted print. (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Tai Young Hahm and various members of Ham family, including Hannah., 1953 November.; 5" x 7" b/w print. (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Tai Young Hahm and various members of Young family., 1953 November.; 5" x 7" b/w print. (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Tai Young Hahm seated with older woman flanked by younger man and woman., 1953 November.; 7" x 5" b/w print. (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Tai Young Hahm with Simon Ham and Clara Cabrinha on his left; two unidentified men on the right., 1953 November.; 8" x 10" b/w print. (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Hannah Chur Ham, Tai Young Ham, Ho Young Ham, Suney Ham, and Juliette Ow., 1953 November.; 5" x 7" b/w print. (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Tai Young Hahm, seated, with four women standing behind him., 1953 November.; 5" x 7" b/w print. (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Korean National Association panoramic group photo of men, women, and children in front of KNA building., 1931 April 19.; 7.25" x 17.5" b/w print. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Group photo of 18 men before a wooden fence., ca. 1915.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 6)
    Ho Young Ham is the last man seated on the right.
  - Large group photos of men, women, and children in front of [Sprecklesville?] church., ca. 1930.; 2 items. (Box 46, Folder 8)
    Ho Young Ham standing top row, fourth from the left. Portrait by H Iwanaga, Sprecklesville, Maui.
  - Photo of industrial plant with train in front [Hawaiian Commercial & Sugar Company?]., ca. 1940.; 1 item. (Box 46, Folder 14)
- Series 9: Printed materials, ca. 1905-1982; 1 box.
  This series largely consists of ephemera. Notable items include clippings of news stories regarding Norman Ham's death in Korea and attempts to bring his daughter, Meiling, to Hawaii during the 1960s. Also includes family records and certificates that document the accomplishments of the Ham family in the early part of the 20th century.
  9A. Ephemera, ca. 1908-1982
  9B. Maps
  9C. Records and certificates, ca. 1905-1979.
  - Subseries 9A: Ephemera, ca. 1908-1982
    Includes clippings, receipts, statements, Korean Pacific Press articles and newsletters, and other miscellaneous material.
    - Songs in the Life printed in Korean., undated.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - Assorted currency., undated.; 5 items. (Box 39, Folder 37)
      $10 Confederate note, 10 Taiwanese yuan, 50 Japanese sen (inscribed "Taken in the Marshall Islands"), 100 yen, and 1 British pound.
    - Booklet--Graduates and activities of The Military Police School ROKA., ca. 1954.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 38)
    - Calendar--"90th Anniversary Celebration of Korean Immigration to Hawaii," produced by Korean Air., 1993.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 39)
      Includes historical images ranging from 1904 to 1952.
    - Clipping--"Japan books: History rewrite draws WWII foes' reaction"., 1982 July 28.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 40)
      Maui News.
    - Clipping--"Korean Vice President Visits Maui"., 1953 November.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 41)
      Two images from Maui News of Tai Young Hahm; one with Simon Ham and Clara Ham Cabrinha.
    - Clipping--"Norman Ham Murdered by Korean Reds: Maui Man Dies for Refusal to Betray USA"., ca. 1950.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 42)
    - Clipping--"Red Cross Assisting: Korean Girl May Join Grandmother on Maui"., ca. 1963 April.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 43)
    - Clipping--"Vice President of Korea Sends Radio Sympathy," Maui News., 1954 April 21.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 44)
    - Clipping--Emperor Hirohito., ca. 1908.; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 45)
    - Korean Benevolent Society of Maui--ACT 60 from Hawaii Department of Taxation regarding property tax exemptions., 1961 May 17.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 1)
      Photocopy of original.
    - Korean Benevolent Society of Maui--Mortuary and Cemetery Practices notice from Hawaiian State Department of Health., 1962 March 13.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 2)
      Photocopy that includes clipping entitled "Exemption Forms for Cemeteries."
    - Korean National Association announcement no. 81--Pa Wang elected. Hawaii Korean Association/Min Chao Ho., 1922.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Korean National Association charters., ca. 1914.; 4 items. (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Korean National Association constitution., ca. 1914.; 4 items. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Korean National Association flyers (or forms) sent to Mr. C.S. Hang., 1953 December 21.; 7 items. (Box 40, Folder 6)
      Cover letter and flyers printed are in Korean.
    - Korean National Association-EXTRA bulletin., 1920 March 10.; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 7)
      Korean text. Regarding death of Tosan Ahu Chan.